lagoonia.com 2016-03-29

# Data Protection Provisions

InnoGames GmbH ("InnoGames") is seriously committed towards protecting the privacy of its users when processing personal data and considers this for all business processes. InnoGames observes the pertinent data protection guidelines. These data protection provisions apply to all services offered on websites operated by InnoGames as well as to portals and to all online games offered by InnoGames ("Website") but not to pages belonging to other providers to which the website may link. In this respect, the data provision conditions of the relevant provider shall apply. 

Here we would like to inform you about the way we collect and use data. By accessing and using the Website, you expressly declare that you approve of the following data protection provisions. At any time, you have the right to revoke any potentially granted approvals to be effective in the future. (Refer to clause 8 "Revocation option"). 

If you have any questions as to how InnoGames uses your personal data, please contact us. **(refer to clause 9 "Questions on data protection and contact")** . 

## 1\. Capturing and use of your personal data by InnoGames 

**1.1** You are anonymous when visiting the website. Any access by a user of the website and any retrieval of a file always collects access data on this process in the protocol file on our server without personal relevance and is stored in our server as follows: Internet Protocol, address / IP address, page from which the file was requested, date, time, browser type and operating system, the page you visited, transferred data quantity, access status (file transferred, file not found, etc.). This data is used to generate statistics which help InnoGames to adapt the services offered to your requirements. 

**1.2** In principle, InnoGames only gains knowledge of, captures and utilises such data which you provide when using the website within the scope of your initial registration and full user registration and, if applicable, when making use of services subject to a charge. Upon initial registration and full user registration, all you need is to give a user name and an email address. 

**1.3** Within the scope of executing the concluded user agreement, in particular with regard to any services subject to a charge which you have selected, you may be required to provide further data, such as for example, full name, address, banking details, credit card numbers, etc. The processing of your requests or your support may also require us to ask for personal data, such as your name, address, email address and telephone number. InnoGames will treat this data confidentially and according to the legal data protection provisions. InnoGames will not pass such information to a third party without your authorisation, other than to the extent required to execute the agreement, to process your requests or for your support. You will find more details regarding passing on data to third parties in clause 6 "Passing personal data to third parties".

**1.4** Here, InnoGames points out that inventory data, utilisation data and statement data according to Articles 14, 15 of the Telecommunications Act or Article 28 of the Federal Data Protection Act are collected, processed and used and this is done, as far as required, even beyond the fulfilment of an agreement. InnoGames reserves the right to store IP addresses and log files for a reasonable period of time after making use of the website to monitor whether the user complies with the conditions and game rules, in particular to ensure proper processing of the payment that you have authorized. This process especially serves to prevent or clarify any cases of abuse and to allow these data to be appropriately passed on to the investigative authorities in specific instances. For the rest, as far as possible, any other evaluation of the data takes place in an anonymized form. Provided there is no pending concrete prosecution action and no preliminary proceedings have been initiated for abuse, the IP addresses and log files are deleted in full at the end of this deadline. 

**1.5** At its own initiative or at your request, InnoGames can complete, correct or delete incomplete, incorrect and/or outdated personal data which InnoGames stores in connection with the operation of the website.

**1.6** Within the scope of legal provisions, InnoGames immediately deletes personal data at the authorised person`s request, provided this does not contradict mandatory legal retention obligations. 

## 2\. Receipt of information about the Game / Newsletter 

With your registration, you confirm that you agree to receive regular email information about the game (e.g. information about updates, etc.) for which you have initially registered / fully registered, as well as a newsletter with current information about other games, etc. You can, at any time, send InnoGames a message that you no longer wish to receive such information. In addition, you always have the option to de-register via a special link located directly in the information about the game or in the newsletter to stop any further receipt. 

_**You can revoke your approval to use your email address to receive information about the game and/or the newsletter at any time with effect for the future**_ (For contact information, refer to clause 8).

## 3\. The use of cookies and web beacons

**3.1 Own cookies and web beacons, advertising by third parties, links to other websites**

In order to design our Internet offer in the most user-friendly manner for you, we, as well as many other companies, also use so-called permanent or temporary cookies and web beacons. Cookies are small text files which are stored on the user's computer and allow for an analysis of how he or she uses the website. This storage, for example, serves to enable an auto-login so that you do not have to identify yourself each time you access the site. No personal identification of the user takes place based on the data stored in the cookie. 

If you do not want cookies to be stored on your computer or wish to be informed of their storage, you can prevent the installation of cookies by a corresponding adjustment to your browser software by selecting the option "do not accept cookies" in your browser settings. Your browser manufacturer's instructions will give you more details on how this works. However, we would like to point out that by preventing cookies, you may find that you cannot use all of the website's functions to the full extent. 

**3.2 Google Analytics**

Google Analytics, a web analysis service from the provider Google Incorporated ("Google"), collects and stores data on the company`s website, enabling the creation of user profiles under pseudonyms. These user profiles serve to analyse visitor behaviour and are evaluated in order to improve and design our offer so as to meet the demands. Cookies can be used for this purpose. You can prevent cookies being installed by making a corresponding adjustment to your browser software; however, we must point out that if you do so, you may not be able to use all the functions on this website to the full extent. The pseudonymous user profiles are not merged with personal data via the pseudonym carrier without an especially granted approval by the affected person. You can, at any time with effect for the future, object to the collection and storing of data for the purpose of web analysis by installing the browser add-on to deactivate Google Analytics. (<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>). 

**3.3. Advertising by third parties, links to other websites, Google AdSense, Facebook button**

 **3.3.1** From time to time, the website may also contain advertising by a third party and interactive links to third party Internet appearances for which InnoGames is not responsible. In particular, InnoGames has no influence on the content and design of the linked external pages or the Internet appearances which you reach via these pages. The relevant providers are exclusively responsible for the content and design of these Internet appearances as well as their compliance with the provisions of the Data Protection Act. 

**3.3.2** The website uses Google AdSense, a web services provided by Google, through which third party advertisements are posted on the website. Within these advertisements, Google can post cookies on the user's hard drive in order to read out the data and can use web beacons (small, invisible graphic files) to collect information. Information created by the cookies and/or web beacons are transferred to a Google server in the USA and processed there. 

**3.3.3** Occasionally, the advertisers or companies use technologies through which advertisements appearing on the InnoGames page are sent directly to your browser, resulting in an automatic transfer of your IP address. The relevant advertisers or companies at times also use cookies as well as other technical means to measure their advertisements' efficiency or to improve their content. This particularly, but not exclusively, affects the allocation of Internet pages to certain interest categories according to your Internet use. In this context, no connection is created between this information and your name, address, telephone number or email address. InnoGames has no influence on this. Data handling by these third parties is therefore not included in this data protection declaration. You can deactivate the use of cookies in your browser settings (refer to clause 3.1). In addition you can prevent the collection of interest-related data and their categorisation by deactivation on [www.google.com/privacy_ads.html.](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

**3.3.4** The website can include the so-called Facebook button "Like", which is exclusively operated by the social network Facebook and thus by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA ("Facebook“). Should you click on the Facebook button "Like" you will be asked by Facebook, if you do not have a Facebook account or are not currently logged into your Facebook account, to register with Facebook in order to use the function. The consequence is that your information is transferred to Facebook. However, should you already have a Facebook account and are logged into your Facebook account parallel to your visit to the website, a connection is automatically created to Facebook's servers, in other words, even without you clicking on the Facebook button; this means that data is transferred to Facebook immediately following your visit to the website. The transfer of your data and the allocation to your Facebook account therefore takes place automatically without any further notification. InnoGames has no influence on this. You can only prevent this transfer if you log out of your Facebook account beforehand. InnoGames expressly points out that you can obtain further information about the data which Facebook collects and your individual rights in this regard from Facebook's website and the data protection provisions stated there. You can read Facebook's data protection provisions on page <http://de-de.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php>

**3.3.5** When you use or connect to a InnoGames website or download a InnoGames mobile app by or through a Third Party Platform, such as Facebook or other social networking site, you allow us to access and/or collect certain information from your Third Party Platform profile/account (such as your Facebook account) or via any cookies placed on your device by such Third Party Platform as permitted by the terms of the agreement and your privacy settings with the Third Party Platform. We will share such information with the Third Party Platform for their use as permitted by the terms of the agreement and your privacy setting with the Third Party Platform.”

We will share some of the information we collect from you upon install of the mobile app with vendors and other service providers who are engaged by or working with us in connection with the operation of the services we provide to you and/or for analytics purposes which may require the reproduction and display of such information in an aggregated and anonymized manner such that will not in any way identify you.

You may "opt out" of the collection of your information for third party analytics purposes by following the directions provided by our third party analytics vendor located at <http://www.mobileapptracking.com/privacy-policy/>. If you “opt out” with our third party analytics provider, that action is specific to the information we collect specifically for that provider, and does not limit our ability to collect information from you, under the terms of this privacy policy, for other vendors.

**3.3.6** In order to improve and optimize our service continuously, we use so-called mobile tracking technologies. For this, we use the services of the adjust GmbH, Saarbrücker Str. 38a, 10405 Berlin, Germany (www.adjust.com). With the help of these services, we collect statistical data on the usage of our apps to be able to constantly improve our offers. While using our apps, information transmitted to us by your device are collected and analyzed. In this respect, the following data are gathered: IP address, which is anonymized right away, MAC address, anonymized Device ID (IDentifier For Advertisers - IDFA or Google Advertiser ID - GAID), browser type, language settings, internet service provider, network status, time zone, URL of the entry and exit pages, date of access and time spent, clickstream data, and other statistical information about the use of our services. A direct individual identification of the user is not possible. The data gathered this way is used to create anonymous user profiles. The data collected with the tracking technologies will not be used to personally identify any visitor of our websites without their explicit consent. The collection and storing of the data can at any time be disabled with effect for the future by adjusting the settings of your mobile device as set out in section §3.5.

**3.3.7** Our website utilizes the “conversion tracking pixel” of Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave., Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA,http://www.facebook.com (“Facebook”) and/or Twitter International Company, The Academy 42, Pearse Street, Dublin 2, Ireland, http://www.twitter.com (“Twitter”). This tool allows us to follow the actions of users after they are redirected to a provider’s website by clicking on a partner’s advertisement. Hence, we are able to record the efficacy of Facebook or Twitter advertisements for statistical and market research purposes. The collected data are anonymous. This means that we cannot see the personal data of any individual user. However, the collected data are saved and processed by Facebook or Twitter. We are informing you on this matter according to our information at this time. Facebook and Twitter are able to connect the data with your Facebook or Twitter account and might use them for their own advertising in accordance with their privacy policies: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/ or https://twitter.com/privacy. The conversion tracking allows Facebook, Twitter and their respective partners to show you advertisements on and outside Facebook or Twitter. In addition, a cookie will be saved onto your computer for these purposes in both cases. Please click here if you would like to revoke your permission: <https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/> or <https://twitter.com/settings/security>. 

**3.3.8** We allow AOL to serve advertising for our websites with AOL’s website(s) and / or third party websites which are our partners or partners of AOL. The following information is inter alia collected by AOL and / or third parties websites: device ID, impressions, clicks, page views etc. You can stop these advertisements and collection of data for the future via opting-out as described here: [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/), <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> or [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

**3.4 Usage via a third-party platform; MobileTracking**

In order to improve and optimize our service continuously, we use so-called mobile tracking technologies. For this, we use the services of the adjust GmbH, Saarbrücker Str. 38a, 10405 Berlin, Germany (www.adjust.com). With the help of these services, we collect statistical data on the usage of our apps to be able to constantly improve our offers. While using our apps, information transmitted to us by your device are collected and analyzed. In this respect, the following data are gathered: IP address, which is anonymized right away, MAC address, anonymized Device ID (IDentifier For Advertisers - IDFA or Google Advertiser ID - GAID), browser type, language settings, internet service provider, network status, time zone, URL of the entry and exit pages, date of access and time spent, clickstream data, and other statistical information about the use of our services. A direct individual identification of the user is not possible. The data gathered this way is used to create anonymous user profiles. The data collected with the tracking technologies will not be used to personally identify any visitor of our websites without their explicit consent. The collection and storing of the data can at any time be disabled with effect for the future by adjusting the settings of your mobile device as set out in section §3.5.

**3.5** You can disable the tracking of your device ID as follows: 

  * In the case of a mobile device of Apple: Open the settings of your mobile device (e.g. iPhone or iPad) and select the menu item “Privacy”. Under “Advertising“ you can turn off the Ad Tracking. 
  * In the case of Android devices: Open the settings in your App list and tap on the “Ad” button. When the Ad window has opened, you can deactivate the Google Advertising ID. 

## 4\. Use of the Scalable Central Measurement Method

The website uses the "Scalable Central Measurement Method / Skalierbares Zentrales Messverfahren" [SZM] of INFOnline (https://www.infoline.de) to determine statistical characteristic values in the use of InnoGames`s offer. Anonymous measured values are collected in this process. For the recognition of computer systems, the SZM audience measurement uses alternatively either a cookie with the identifier "ivwbox.de" or a signature which is created from various information automatically transferred by your computer. IP addresses are not stored via this method and only processed in anonymised form.

The audience measurement was developed in consideration of data protection. The goal of the audience measurement is to statistically determine user intensity and the number of users of a specific website. Individual users are not identified at any point in time. Your identity is always protected. You will not receive any advertising via the system. 

For websites which are members of the IVW German Audit Bureau of Circulation (Informationsgemeinschaft zur Feststellung der Verbreitung von Werbeträgern e.V.,http://www.ivw.eu) [Information association to determine the distribution of advertisers] or that participate in the study "Internet Facts" organised by the Arbeitsgemeinschaft Online-Forschung e.V. [Work Group Online Research](AGOF -http://www.agof.de), user statistics are published monthly by the AGOF and the Arbeitsgemeinschaft Media-Analyse e.V. (agma -http://www.agma-mmc.de), as well as the IVW and can beviewed at http://www.agof.de, http://www.agma-mmc.de and http://www.ivw.eu.

In addition to the publication of measurement data, the IVW also regularly checks the SZM process to ensure that it is used according to regulations and in line with data protection.

You can find additional information about the SZM process on the website of INFOline GmbH (https://www.infoline.de), the operators of the SZM process, as well as the data protection website of AGOF (http://agof.de/datenschutz) and the data protection website of IVW (http://www.ivw.eu).

You can object to the data processing by the SZM under the following link: [http://optout.ivwbox.de](http://optout.ivwbox.de/)

## 5.Data security

5.1 At all times, InnoGames strives to take precautions, to a reasonable extent, to prevent unauthorised access to your personal data as well as the unauthorised use or falsification of theses data and to minimise the corresponding risks. Nevertheless, the provision of personal data, wheter this is done personally, by telephone or over the Internet, is always associated with risks and no technological system is fully exempt from the possibility of manipulation or sabotage. 

5.2 InnoGames processes the data collected from you according to the German Data Protection Law. All employees are obliged to comply with data secrecy and the data protection provisions and are instructed accordingly. In the event of payment transactions, your data is transferred encrypted through the use of the SSL process.

## 6\. Passing personal data to third parties

**6.1** InnoGames will in principle only pass your personal and/or billing-related data to third parties, that is to partner companies, other companies cooperating with InnoGames, external service providers and investigative authorities as far as this is required to fulfil the agreement and for the aforementioned purposes, in particular for payment processing as well as to protect other users or as provided by law. Payment processing takes place via external service providers (e.g. credit card companies, banks, PaySafe, Wallie, Clickandbuy, Moneybookers, Paypal, Global Collect). Your protected interests are considered according to the legal provisions. External service providers are obliged to treat your data confidentially and securely and may only use your data as far as this is required to fulfil their duties. We point out that InnoGames may be obliged to pass data on the basis of legal provisions (e.g. passing to investigative authorities). Data are only passed as far as this is required or prescribed by law.

In the event of payment arrears, InnoGames will, if necessary, instruct a collection company or a lawyer to collect the payable amount. The required data are passed for this purpose and utilised in compliance with all data protection guidelines. 

**6.2** In other instances, InnoGames will only pass your personal data which you provided to InnoGames during the course of your registration and to process your order if you have previously given your express approval.

## 7\. Changes 

InnoGames can change these data protection provisions or change the content of the page or change or block access to these pages at any time. InnoGames will use suitable means to point out such changes.

## 8\. Option of revocation and data deletion

**8.1** If you wish to revoke your approval to send information about the game or the newsletter, please send an email to: privacy@innogames.com by stating your user name and the email address to which the information and/or the newsletter is being sent. Each of our newsletters contains a link which gives you the oppportunity to revoke your approval and to cancel the newsletter. 

**8.2** At your request, InnoGames will immediately delete personal data, that is data which include the user`s information about personal and factual circumstances, unless mandatory obligations to preserve records or other obligations contradict such a deletion. 

## 9\. Questions on data protection and contact / information, correction, deletion and blocking

You are always entitled to request information about any of your data that InnoGames has stored, as well as their origin and recipient and the purpose it was stored for. If you have any questions about data protection or if you wish to correct, block or delete your profile or any of your personal data, or if you would like to revoke a granted authorization regarding the use of your customer data or e-mail address, please contact the following and also provide your username and your e-mail address: 

InnoGames GmbH  
Friesenstraße 13  
20097 Hamburg  
Germany 

Fax: +49 40 7889335-200  

Status: February 2013  
© Copyright InnoGames 2009 – 2016. All rights reserved.
